Guide to the Jere Link Papers, 1914-2016 and undated RL.11690
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jere Link papers
1914-2016 and undated, bulk 1975-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Link, Jere
RL.11690
7.5 Linear Feet
.01 Gigabytes
The Jere Link papers comprise his private diaries and journals, creative and scholarly writings, lecture notes and teaching materials, along with incoming correspondence. Diaries and journals contain Link's personal thoughts and comments on his life, activities, creative and scholarly work, and relationships. Link was very open regarding his inner thoughts and concerns, and very frank about his sexual activities and his life as a gay man. His writings include general notebooks with drafts of creative work, screenplays, book proposals and drafts, Link's dissertation, along with articles, poetry, and short stories. There are teaching materials primarily featuring Link's handwritten lecture notes for his classes, along with additional related maps, handouts, photographs, exams and other materials. In addition, there are incoming personal letters and cards, along with some professional letters regarding Link's institutional appointments, writing, and Fulbright travel grant.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Diaries and Journals, Writings, Teaching Materials, and Correspondence.
Biographical / Historical
Jere Hudson Link was born on June 12, 1951, in Mobile, Alabama. He graduated with honors from McGill Institute High School in Mobile in 1969. He attended the University of Alabama, received his undergraduate degree with special honors in German from the University of Texas at Austin (1973), a Master of Arts in Comparative Literature from University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (1975) and his Ph.D. in History from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (1988). Jere was awarded the Fulbright Scholarship in his pursuit of his graduate studies. During his career he taught at Virginia Tech, The Westminster Schools, Pace Academy, and Kennesaw State University. He was honored as Georgia Star Teacher of the Year in 1997 and regional Star Teacher in 1993 and 2004. He died in Atlanta, Georgia, on March 15, 2018.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Jere Link Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018.
Collection Overview
Diaries and journals contain Link's personal thoughts and comments on his life, activities, creative and scholarly work, and relationships. Link was very open regarding his inner thoughts and concerns, and very frank about his sexual activities and his life as a gay man. His writings include general notebooks with drafts of creative work, screenplays, book proposals and drafts, Link's dissertation, along with articles, poetry, and short stories. There are teaching materials primarily featuring Link's handwritten lecture notes for his classes, along with additional related maps, handouts, photographs, exams and other materials. In addition, there are incoming personal letters and cards, along with some professional letters regarding Link's institutional appointments, writing, and Fulbright travel grant. Items pre-dating Link include two articles on Greece printed in 1914 and 1916, along with some family history materials dated 1928.
Conditions Governing Access
Some materials in this collection are electronic records that require special equipment. Contact Research Services with questions.
Teachers -- Georgia; Gay men -- Southern States; Gay men -- Sexual behavior; Gay men -- Diaries; Creative writing.; Link, Jere
- Diaries and Journals, 1975-2011
  Scope and Contents
  The Diaries and Journals Series contain Link's personal thoughts and comments on his life, activities, creative and scholarly work, and relationships. Link was very open regarding his inner thoughts and concerns, and very frank about his sexual activities and his life as a gay man. He considered himself a scholar and a creative writer, so his entries generally do not mention current events or politics. Some entries in German.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1975 (Box 5)
  - 1976?-1977? (Box 5)
  - 1978 (Box 5)
  - 1979 (Box 5)
  - Journal leaves, 1979 (Box 4)
  - 1980 (Box 5)
  - 1981? (Box 5)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 5)
  - 1982 (Box 5)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 5)
  - 1983, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - 1984 (Box 5)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - 1985 (Box 5)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - 1986 (Box 5)
  - 1986-1988 (Box 5)
  - 1988-1990 (Box 5)
  - 1990-1991 (Box 5)
  - 1992-1994 (Box 5)
  - 1994-2001 (Box 5)
  - 2005, 2011 (Box 5)
- Writings, 1928-2016 and undated
  The Writings Series contains Link's creative and scolarly writing, much of it undated. There are general notebooks with drafts of creative work (some with scattered lecture notes included), screenplays, book proposals and drafts, Link's dissertation, along with articles, poetry, and short stories. Much of the material in the series remained unpublished. See the Diaries and Journals Series for Link's commentary about individual items in the series. For the writings in digital formats, some disks contain parts of different projects stored together. In these cases, they often appear in the General sub-series.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Articles, 1982-1993 and undated
    - Postdoc applications, 1993 (Box 3)
    - Articles, undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Conference papers, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
    - Papers submitted for coursework, 1982-1984; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Books, 1928-2011 and undated
    Conditions Governing Access
    Some materials in this sub-series are electronic records that require special equipment. Contact Research Services with questions.
    - Confession before Communion, undated (Box 2)
    - Floating Island notes, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Floating Island notes, 1994-2011 (Box 2)
    - Floating Island, original?, undated (Box 2)
    - Floating Island, undated (Box 2)
    - Floating Island, 1st draft?, 1976? (Box 4)
    - Floating Island, 2nd draft, 1990; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Floating Island, draft, undated (Box 4)
    - Floating Island (backup), 2002-2004; 14 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0003)
      Contains document files.
    - FI backups, 1987-1994; 16 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0008)
    - FI backup, second half, 2000-2004; 13 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0012)
    - FI backups (2004), 1993-2004; 13 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0013)
    - Pts of floating island, 2001-2004; 41 files; approximately 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0020)
    - In Debt to National Literature, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - In Debt to National Literature, chap. 3 on, undated; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Members of the Schillerstiftung, appendix, undated (Box 2)
    - King of the City, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Legion, undated (Box 2)
    - Moving Pictures, scattered pages, undated (Box 2)
    - Moving Pictures, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Moving pictures (backups), 2000-2003; 17 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0017)
    - M.P. backup (2004), 2002; 11 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0004)
    - Pushkin book, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Untitled, undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Book proposals, 1991 and undated (Box 2)
    - Dossier of material for a biography, 1928-2013 (Box 2)
  - Dissertation, 1987-1993 and undated
    - Dissertation (photocopy), undated; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Wilhelm, 1987-1992; 4 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 2, Disk RL11690-FL5-0021)
    - Data: Stiftung cases, 1988; 11 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0018)
      Contains document and unidentified files.
    - Dissertation: conclu, appendices, 1987-1988; 10 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0009)
    - Chap iv6, 1987-1989; 13 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0011)
    - Codebook/append B; biblio, 1987-1993; 26 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0015)
    - Chap. 2 (schillr.doc): good; Chap. 5 (schillr.doc): good; Chap. 3 (schillr.doc): good, 1987-1988; 9 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0021)
    - Compute Conclu Codebook Biblio, 1988-1993; 10 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 2, Disk RL11690-FL5-0019)
    - Appendix A, Appen B, Intro, 1987-1993; 8 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 2, Disk RL11690-FL5-0020)
  - General, 1980-2002 and undated
    - Commonplace book, 1980 (Box 1)
    - General writing, notebook, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Notebook, 1991-1992? (Box 1)
    - Notebook, 1998? (Box 1)
    - Notebook, undated; 6 folders (Box 1)
    - Essays/AP Fur Source Book/ Newer Legion/UP, 1997-2004; 27 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0001)
    - "Queer" stuff, 1987-2002 (bulk 1994-20010); 37 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0006)
    - Vol. III Making Time, Goverenor and Russing Princess, Hideaway, King of the City, Hotlanta, 2001; 10 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0016)
    - PC/SAS back-up "schiller" w REA test 2 old 2006, 1988; 5 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0022)
    - Copy/1987, 1980-1999 (bulk 1988-1995); 18 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 1, Disk RL11690-FL5-0001)
    - Gulf Coast Tales, Chairwoman Stuff, HAW, AP Stuff, 1993-1997; 34 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 1, Disk RL11690-FL5-0007)
      Contains document files. There is also draft correspondence and teaching-related materials on mixed with literary writings.
    - CBE, Spring Syllabus 1996, Personals 2000, Hotlanta Novel, 1996-2000; 26 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 1, Disk RL11690-FL5-0010)
      Contains document files. There is also teaching-related materials mixed with literary and personal writings.
    - Untitled disk, 1996; 19 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 1, Disk RL11690-FL5-0011)
    - Varia 97-98, 1997-2000; 11 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 1, Disk RL11690-FL5-0012)
    - Untitled disk, 1987-1993; 5 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 1, Disk RL11690-FL5-0015)
    - Untitled disk, 1993-1994; 21 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 2, Disk RL11690-FL5-0016)
      Contains document and image files.
    - Dssn backups and Governor and German Princess, 1987-2002 (bulk 1995-2002); 45 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0005)
    - Theater doc / Ch.6, 1987-1993; 5 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 2, Disk RL11690-FL5-0018)
    - Backup: Hiway 90, 1987-1999 (bulk 1995-1999); 15 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 2, Disk RL11690-FL5-0026)
    - Backup: Gulf Coast Tales, 1987-1996 (bulk 1995-1996); 6 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 2, Disk RL11690-FL5-0027)
    - Backup: Gulf Coast Tales and Epilogue, 1987-1997 (bulk 1996-1997); 8 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 2, Disk RL11690-FL5-0028)
  - Poetry, 1977-2016 and undated
    - Attempts at Poetry, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Gedichte, 2016 (Box 3)
    - Poems, 1977-1986 (Box 4)
    - Poems, undated (Box 3)
  - Screenplays, 1981?-2003 and undated
    - Book: The Screenwriter's Bible by David Trottier, 1998 (Box 1)
    - Screenplay fragments, undated (Box 1)
    - Legion notes, undated (Box 1)
    - Sketches of Legion story, 1981? (Box 1)
    - The Legion, undated (Box 1)
    - The Legion, annotated draft 1, undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - The Legion, annotated draft 2, undated (Box 1)
    - Legion, final draft?, undated (Box 1)
    - New "Legion", 2000-2003; 21 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0014)
    - Legion screenplay, 1999-2003; 23 files; approximately 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0019)
    - Wild Dogs, Wolves, notes and short draft, undated (Box 1)
    - Wild Dogs, Wolves, annotated draft, undated (Box 1)
    - Wild Dogs, Wolves, undated (Box 1)
  - Short Stories, 1978-2009 and undated
    - The Governor and the Russian Princess drafts, 1978 and undated (Box 3)
    - The Hideaway, undated (Box 3)
    - The Hideaway, annotated, undated (Box 3)
    - Deep south pt 1 Hideaway, 1988-2002 (bulk 2001-2002); 15 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0007)
    - Moving Pictures excerpt, 2009 (Box 3)
- Teaching Materials, 1914-2016 and undated
  The Teaching Materials Series primarily features Link's handwritten lecture notes for his classes, including additional related maps, handouts, photographs, exams and other materials. While most of the lecture notes were foldered according to Link's folder titles, there are several folders of loose lecture notes found in the the collection that are not arranged. Includes two research items regarding Greece that were published in 1914 and 1916. See also the general notebooks in the Writings Series for scattered lecture notes.
  - 1860's Symposium, 2003 (Box 3)
  - 1880's, undated (Box 4)
  - 19th c. Imperialism, undated (Box 3)
  - History 102, 19th and 20th centuries, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Enrichment Night, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Ancient and Medieval History, 2004 and undated (Box 3)
  - AP European History, undated (Box 4)
  - Articles on Greece, 1914, 1916 (Box 3)
  - Comments, undated (Box 3)
  - Domestic Unification, undated (Box 4)
  - End of the Holy Roman Empire 1792-1806, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Enlightenment and romanticism, 1990 (Box 3)
  - European Philosophy, undated (Box 4)
  - French Revolution Notes, undated (Box 4)
  - From the Dialogue, Phaidros, undated (Box 3)
  - Fulbright Receipts Book, 1991 (Box 3)
  - German Cultural Revival, 1998 (Box 3)
  - German Culture, 1991 (Box 4)
  - German honors VI, 2004-2005; 7 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 4, Disk RL11690-FL3-0023)
  - Germans 20th century, undated (Box 3)
  - Grant Proposal, 1996-1997; 12 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 1, Disk RL11690-FL5-0003)
  - KSU: Cultures, Empires, Civilizations, 2012-2016 (Box 3)
  - KSU Orientation, 2016 (Box 3)
  - KSU: Rome, 2016 (Box 3)
  - Lectures and Notes, undated; 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Lectures and notes (oversize), undated (Box 4)
  - Logic and Fallacies, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Maps, Pictures, Factoids, undated (Box 3)
  - Melodrama, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Mercantilism, Revolution and Capitalism, undated (Box 3)
  - Noble Deeds and Thoughts, undated (Box 4)
  - Notebooks, undated; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Notebooks (oversize), undated (Box 4)
  - Philosophy, 2008 and undated (Box 3)
  - Philosophy Lectures, undated (Box 4)
  - Politics and Ideal State, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Postmodernism, undated (Box 4)
  - Renaissance, undated (Box 4)
  - Romanticism, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Sabbatical year 1999-2000, 2000-2006; 21 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 3, Disk RL11690-FL3-0002)
  - Weimar Germany, undated (Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1975-2006 and undated
  The Correspondence Series contains primarily incoming personal letters and cards, along with some professional letters regarding Link's institutional appointments, writing, and Fulbright travel grant. There are only a few letters by Link. Topics include academia, popular culture, philosophy, an current events. Many letters are in German.
  - 1975-1986 (Box 4)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - 1992-1994 (Box 4)
  - 1995-1997 (Box 4)
  - 2002-2006 (Box 4)
  - Undated (Box 4)
  - Letters to Jeanne Ortega, 1995-1999; 12 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL11690-SET-0001, Folder 1, Disk RL11690-FL5-0002)